# JORDEN WHITEFIELD

PhD Computer Science

WHO AM I? SKILLS

I have a passion for building tools and working openly with development teams to find and solve security issues. I enjoy sharing my research, in collaboration with academia and industry, with the security community. A strong team player who appreciates working with different cultures and diverse backgrounds.

Programming: python, java

Mobile Dev: android

Other: docker, linux, git, agile planning

#### **EXPERIENCE**

9/2021 - Present Security Engineer Wolt, Finland

6/2019 - 8/2021 Security Specialist Ethical Hacker Ericsson, Finland

Performed penetration tests for products across the business portfolio including complex 5G networks, cloud-native services, and mobile apps;

Collaborated with product development teams to identify how to harden their products; Contributed to the product security hardening instructions;

Assisted the Product Security Incident Response Team (PSIRT) to verify security findings raised by customers/researchers and identify fixes;

Collaborated with the embedded radio system teams and produced threat models.

1/2019 - 6/2019 Visiting Post Doctoral Researcher Aalto University, Finland

Supervised two MSc students reports on Android security;

Supported teaching and grading of CS-E4310: Mobile Systems Security.

2017 PhD Internship Thales Group, UK

Implemented a security protocol for connected vehicles from my research; led the project and defined the software requirements; presented outcomes to stakeholders for internal review.

Supervised a junior team member in the development of the demonstrator;

2013 – 2014 Associate Software Engineer Accenture, UK

Developed mobile applications for Android and iOS; extended legacy UK government software systems with a RESTful API layer to integrate with modern systems.

systems with a resolution megrate with modern systems

**EDUCATION** 

2015 - 2019 PhD Computer Science University of Surrey, UK

Thesis title: Formal Analysis and Applications of Direct Anonymous Attestation; Completed a Graduate Certificate in Learning and Teaching; lab demonstrator;

Awarded an EPSRC UK Impact Acceleration Account for £47k that implemented a vehicular communication platform in a relevant automotive lab environment.

Authored an open source sublime text plugin for the tamarin prover security analysis tool.

2011 - 2015 BSc Computer Science, First class honours University of Surrey, UK

Received the EDF Best Digital Project Prize for achieving the highest mark for my dissertation;

Received a scholarship from the University of Surrey for performance in my studies;

Extra-curricular: President of the Computer Science Society and led coding workshops. Key modules: Computer Security, Information Security Management, Software Engineering.

**PUBLICATIONS** 

2020 Formal Analysis and Implementation of a TPM 2.0-based Direct Anonymous Attestation

Scheme

ACM Asia Conference on Computer and Communications Security, ASIACCS, Taipei, Taiwan.

2019	A Symbolic Analy	sis of FCC-based	Direct Anony	mous Attestation
2013	A Syllibolic Allac	Jaia Oi ECC-Daaco	I DII CCL AIIOIII	/IIIOus Allesialioii

IEEE European Symposium on Security and Privacy, EuroSP, Stockholm, Sweden.

#### 2017 Privacy-Enhanced Capabilities for VANETS Using Direct Anonymous Attestation

IEEE Vehicular Networking Conference, VNC, Torino, Italy.

#### Formal Analysis of V2X Revocation Protocols

Security and Trust Management, STM, Oslo, Norway.

## 2016 Symbolic Reachability Analysis of B Through ProB and LTSmin

Integrated Formal Methods, IFM, Reykjavik, Iceland.

#### **TALKS**

2020 **Direct Anonymous Attestation** 

The Trusted Computing Group - Attestation Working Group, Online

2019 Direct Anonymous Attestation in the Wild

IACR Real World Crypto Symposium, San Jose, California, USA

**Container Security** 

Ericsson Network Security Seminar, Stockholm, Sweden

### 2018 Formal Analysis and Applications of Direct Anonymous Attestation

1st Annual Research Institute for Secure Systems & Embedded Hardware conference, London,

United Kingdom

REFERENCES	KEY INFORMATION	HOBBIES
Available on request.	British Citizen	Board Games
	Full UK Driving License	Baking
		Badminton
		Hiking